<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="38"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[TABLE OF CONTENTS




                 NO.                            DESCRIPTION                                    PAGE


                  1     ABOUT THE COURSE                                                         1


                  2     ABOUT UCE                                                                1


                  3     OUR RESPONSIBILITY                                                     2 – 10


                  4     NAME OF PROGRAMME/ DEPARTMENT/ FACULTY                                   11


                  5     NAME OF PROJECT                                                          11


                  6     NAME OF LECTURER/ TEAM LEADERS                                           11


                  7     DATE OF PROJECT                                                          12



                  8     ORGANISATIONAL BACKGROUND                                             13 – 15


                  9     OBJECTIVES                                                               16


                  10    STAKEHOLDERS                                                             16


                  11    NUMBER OF PARTICIPANTS FROM THE COMMUNITY                                17


                  12    NUMBER OF PARTICIPANTS FROM UM                                           17


                  13    PROJECT PROGRESSION PERIOD                                               17


                  14    PROGRAMME TENTATIVE AND ACTIVITIES                                    18 – 32



                  15    ISSUES/CHALLENGES                                                        33


                  16    NEWSPAPER TEMPLATE                                                       34


                  17    CLOSURE                                                                  36]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[ABOUT THE COURSE




               GKR1016 - BASICS GRAPHICS USING COMPUTER


                       This course exposes students to the basic techniques in the art of graphics using computer

               such as operating the graphics software, determining the size of the graphical edits, and choosing


               appropriate colours and themes for each graphic manipulation. Students will also learn the various


               techniques and tools to produce graphics in the computer. Through this course, students’ interest

               will be nurtured in graphics using computer via teamwork activities. Teaching and learning will

               be conducted through experiential learning and collective problem-solving with the community.



                       At the end of this course, students are able to understand and practise the basic techniques

               in the art of graphics using computer and capable of becoming a citizen with an inquisitive mind


               based on interest.






               ABOUT UCE



                       University  Community  Engagement,  known  as  UCE,  in  University  of  Malaya  is  a

               programme initiated by Centre for Initiation of Talent and Industrial Training (CITRA) University

               of Malaya to inculcate human values among undergraduates. It is important for the future graduates


               to build a holistic character which includes their love for the community. CITRA is on the right


               track with the implementation of UCE. UCE is conducted by each co-curriculum course student

               as a requirement to pass the subject. Generally, students plan and execute the whole volunteering

               programme on their own. This enhances the organisational skills among the undergraduates.







                                                              1]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[OUR RESPONSIBILITY



               Group 1 – Photography and Videography Bureau




































                              Muhammad Amirul Najmi bin Harum            AIF170013

                              Muhammad Sarip bin Nasaruddin              AIF170014

                              Mohamed Ashraf bin Rosidi                  AIF170010


               Our job scopes:

                   •  To  arrange  a  photoshoot  session  of  the  whole  GKR1016  team  with  the  pupils  and


                       administrators of Pure Life Society.

                   •  To document each team activities by taking pictures and videos during UCE.


                   •  To edit photos and video took in the UCE.


                   •  To provide PhotoScape Designing Tutorial Classes for the people of Pure Life Society.

                   •  To be involved in the stair painting during UCE.


                                                              2]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Group 2 – Finance and Secretarial Bureau







































                              Lek Jian An                                WIC 170036

                              Choi Meng Hui                              WIC 170021

                              Ng Jih Yann                                WIF 170109

                              Lim Ze Dong                                WIE170025


               Our job scopes:

                   •  To manage and control the UCE budget.


                   •  To collect funding and document the receipts systematically.

                   •  To prepare meeting minutes and paper works.


                   •  To provide PhotoScape Designing Tutorial Classes for the people of Pure Life Society.

                   •  To be involved in the stair painting during UCE.





                                                              3]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Group 3 – Photography and Videography Bureau




































                            Siti Sarah binti Azhari                                                             LIA170121

                            Sasikala A/P Sevaneswaran                                                    SIC160067
                            Sharifah Nurul Ain Aqilah binti Wan Abdurahman            IIO160027

                           Alya Sakina binti Sazali                                  WIC170009

                            Muhammad Faizi bin Abd Wasir                             KIA170058



               Our job scopes:

                   •  To  arrange  a  photoshoot  session  of  the  whole  GKR1016  team  with  the  people  and

                       administrators of Pure Life Society.


                   •  To document each team activities by taking pictures and videos during UCE.


                   •  To edit photos and video took during UCE.

                   •  To provide Photoscape Designing Tutorial Classes for the people of Pure Life Society


                   •  To be involved in the stair painting during UCE.


                                                              4]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Group 4 – STEM Chemistry Experiment Bureau























                              Lim Jue Yi                                                         SIQ170013

                              Tan Woon Yan                                                  SID170054

                              Tan Jia Shen                                                      LIA170128

                              Sarah Syazwina Mohd Rozaidi                         WIF170146
                              Tasnim binti Mohd Naim                                  WIE170043





               Our job scopes:


                   •  To handle the science exhibition during UCE.


                   •  To collect chemistry experiment videos from every group.

                   •  To collect apparatus and materials needed for the experiments during UCE.


                   •  To arrange people to help demonstrate the experiments.

                   •  To provide Photoscape Designing Tutorial Classes for the people of Pure Life Society.


                   •  To be involved in the computer lab redesigning.



                                                              5]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[Group 5 – STEM Physics Experiment Bureau


































                              Ammar Eizlan bin Norzaim                          KIE160011

                              Syahirah bt Abd Malek                             TIF160016

                              Alia Athirah binti Zainudin                       TIF160030
                              Muhammad Amzar bin Mohamad Nasir                  KIE160043

                              Muhammad Amirul Iman bin Zalzilah Rashidi         KIE160050



               Our job scopes:



                   •  To handle the science exhibition during UCE.

                   •  To collect physics experiment videos from every group.


                   •  To collect apparatus and materials needed for the experiments during UCE.

                   •  To arrange people to help demonstrate the experiments.


                   •  To provide Photoscape Designing Tutorial Classes for the people of Pure Life Society.

                   •  To be involved in the computer lab redesigning.



                                                              6]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Group 6 – Programme Planning Bureau





































                                        Chew Jia Xian                                                         KIA17001

                                        Darani Mohamed Amine                                        WIC170704

                                        Leong Zi Wei                                                          WIE170023

                                        Looi Lay Foon                                                         AII170016

                                        Wong Munn Fong                                                   WIC170087



               Our job scopes:


                   •  To plan and ensure the whole programme flow are carried out smoothly.


                   •  To contact the person in charge from Pure Life Society.

                   •  To conduct and be in charge of the programme during UCE.


                   •  To provide Photoscape Designing Tutorial Classes for the people of Pure Life Society

                   •  To be involved in the road painting during UCE.



                                                              7]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[Group 7 – STEM Mathematics Experiment Bureau




































                                     Satis Kumar a/l Permal              WIC170075

                                     Teoh Bee Ee                         WIC170084
                                     Eunice Cheng Hui Yen                WIE170012

                                     Chan Ka Chun                        WIF170025

                                     Lau Zi Yee                          WIC170035



               Our job scopes:



                   •  To handle the science exhibition during UCE.

                   •  To collect mathematics experiment videos from every group.

                   •  To collect apparatus and materials needed for the experiments during UCE.


                   •  To arrange people to help demonstrate the experiments.


                   •  To provide Photoscape Designing Tutorial Classes for the people of Pure Life Society.

                   •  To be involved in the road painting during UCE


                                                              8]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[Group 8 – Logistic and Resource Bureau





































                              Tong Wen Qi                                EIA160322

                              Choo Keat Kin                              EIA160291

                              Choo Yan                                   EIA160292

                              Gan Lie Sha                                EIA160296

                              Ameen Gabr Alshaghdari                     KIL160709



               Our job scopes:


                   •  To prepare all the resources needed during the UCE visit to Pure Life Society


                   •  To arrange the transport for the UCE visit to Pure Life Society

                   •  To provide Photoscape Designing Tutorial Classes for the people of Pure Life Society


                   •  To be involved in the road painting during UCE.






                                                              9]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[Group 9 – STEM Biology Experiment Bureau



































                                 Mohamad Zaidan bin Mohamad Khalil       WIE170029

                                 Afrie Irham bin Akram                   WIF170005

                             Melvin Anak Edward Tuah                     WIF170076

                             Abdur Rahman bin Mohd Nor                   IIS170001

                             Muhammad Badrul Aiman bin Ahmad Nadzri   WIC170046



               Our job scopes:


                   •  To handle the science exhibition during UCE.


                   •  To collect physics experiment videos from every group.

                   •  To collect apparatus and materials needed for the experiments during UCE.


                   •  To arrange people to help demonstrate the experiments.

                   •  To provide Photoscape Designing Tutorial Classes for the people of Pure Life Society.


                   •  To be involved in the computer lab redesigning.


                                                             10]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[NAME OF PROGRAMME/ DEPARTMENT/ FACULTY




               GKR1016 – Basics Graphics Using Computer


               Co-Curriculum Course



               Centre for Initiation of Talent and Industrial Training (CITRA)






               NAME OF PROJECT




               University Engagement Programme (UCE) at Pure Life Society






               NAME OF COURSE COORDINATOR/ LECTURER




               Dr. Wong Seng Yue





























                                                             11]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[NAME OF BUREAU LEADERS




                 Name                                         Position


                 Tong Wen Qi                                  Logistic and Resource Bureau


                 Siti Sarah Binti Azhari                      Photography and Videography Bureau


                 Chew Jia Xian                                Programme Planning Bureau


                 Lek Jian An                                  Finance and Secretarial Bureau


                 Mohamad Zaidan bin Mohamad Khalil  STEM Biology Experiment Bureau


                 Lim Jue Yi                                   STEM Chemistry Experiment Bureau


                 Ammar Eizlan Bin Norzaim                     STEM Physics Experiment Bureau


                 Satis Kumar a/l Permal                       STEM Mathematics Experiment Bureau











               DATE OF PROJECT



               18th November 2018


















                                                             12]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[ORGANISATIONAL BACKGROUND







                       Generally, Pure Life Society is a non-profit

               organization (NGO) actively serving the orphans and


               underprivileged children aged 7 to 17 years old. This


               centre was established 67 years ago and still standing

               strong at Batu 6, Jalan Puchong, Wilayah Persekutuan

               Kuala Lumpur, 58200, Kuala Lumpur.



                       From the very beginning, Pure Life Society upholds a genuine mission to promote the spirit

               of unity in the face of diversity through service to the community irrespective of race or religion.


               For the realization of this mission, Pure Life Society’s committee members have instilled strong

               belief among all in which they recognize all things as one. They believe in One God, One World


               and One Race. This message directly conveys that well-being is for all human beings without any

               biases or discrimination towards the children. These children deserve to live a decent and peaceful


               life like anybody else; it is their human right. Decent life here refers to the availability of good

               opportunity of education which then leads to a successful career.


                       Pure Life Society typically engaged with the kids by these four main activities. Below are


               listed down the activities: -


               1. Spiritual Activities



                   •  To promote respect and appreciation of all religious schools of thought.

                   •  Example: Reciting prayers before meals.




                                                             13]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[2. Sports Activities



                   •  To ensure children are actively and physically fit.

                   •  Successfully built badminton courts and futsal ground for the kids to play.



               3. Vocational Education Activities


                   •  Importance given to skills.


                   •  A few children have been sent off to vocational colleges (e.g. TEKAT college in Kajang

                       for automobile technology training).


                   •  Other skill activities include yoga and Indian classical dance.


               4. Facilities



                   •  Some great facilities are prepared in the centre including free medical check-up, laundry

                       sewing and handicraft, library, computer labs and bread-making services.





































                                                             14]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[HISTORICAL BACKGROUND






                       H.H.  Swami  Satyananda,  born  in  1906,  was  the

               Founder-President of the Pure Life Society who, during the


               years 1945 to 1951, was involved in relief work among the

               poor, the orphans, and the displaced children both in Malaya


               and Singapore. At that time, Mother (then Sister) Mangalam,

               the present President now, was already working closely with


               him. In the year 1949, he started off the Pure Life Society as a

               paper organization, aiming to promote multi-racial and multi


               religious  understanding  through  lectures,  forums  and

               programmes that promote interaction through inter-faith conventions and services somewhere at

               the Leper settlement, old folks’ homes, Serendah Boys’ Home, and the like.



                       After that, the Society was registered in 15 July 1950 as a proper society as they found the

               need to establish a home for orphans and underprivileged children that resulted from World War


               II. Eventually, in 1952, the first few barrack-like buildings were built by the Pure Life Society.


                       In  1961,  following  Swami  Satyananda’s  demise,  Mother  (then  Sister)  Mangalam  was


               appointed as President by the virtue of the Society’s Ordinance.














                                                             15]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[OBJECTIVES




               1. To build up a caring community


               2. To give back to the society



               3. To promote the positive values of self-fulfilment


               4. To empower under-privileged children


               5. To utilize community resources



               6. To enhance the sense of social belongings






               STAKEHOLDERS



               Children of Pure Life Society






               Question: Is this the first time you joined this programme with this community? Please state.


               (1st time, 2nd time, etc.)


               Yes,  it  is  our  first  time  joining  this  UCE  programme  with  the  community  and  contributed


               something to them.















                                                             16]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[NUMBER  OF  PARTICIPANTS  FROM  THIS  COMMUNITY  THAT  ARE


               INVOLVED



               50 students from Pure Life Society.






               NUMBER OF PARTICIPANTS FROM UM THAT ARE INVOLVED



               41 students.






               PROJECT PROGRESSION PERIOD



               9 hours and 30 minutes.



































                                                             17]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[PROGRAMME TENTATIVE



                          th
               Date  : 18  November 2018


               Venue : The Pure Life Society, Jalan Puchong



                     Time                                       Activities

                   0730-0815     UM participants gather to depart to Pure Life Society with their respective


                                 group

                   0815-0830     Reach Pure Life Society and start registration


                   0830-1230         •  Computer lab painting and designing

                                     •  Wall painting/Stair painting


                                     •  Road painting

                   1230-1330     Lunch/Prayer Zohor


                   1330-1530     Computer lab session (Photoscape Designing Tutorial Class)

                   1530-1730         •  STEM competition (demonstrating several science experiments)


                                     •  Photo session

                   1730-1750     Activities end, and groups dismiss



















                                                             18]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[ACTIVITIES




               COMPUTER LAB PAINTING AND DESIGNING



                         This computer lab painting and designing activity was delegated to 15 students from

                 Groups 4, 5 and 9 respectively. The computer lab needed a fresh redesign to create  a more


                 harmonious environment for the children as well as to provide for a good change of scenery.


                 This activity involved four process, which are planning, cleaning, painting and designing. It was

                 carried out from 8.30am to 12.30pm.



























                                      Students were preparing the paint before beginning the activity


               Step 1: Planning



                        The first step, planning, was to ensure that the overall redesign suits the harmonious


                 feeling and to create a blue print for the upcoming steps and procedures.





                                                             19]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[Thorough planning is done before anything
                                                        is carried out



               Step 2: Cleaning



                        The second step, cleaning, was to ensure that dust and dirt were removed in order


                 to allow the smooth layering of paint on the surface of the walls of the computer lab.






















                                       Computer lab walls are cleaned very carefully before
                                                           painting




                                                             20]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[Step 3: Painting



                        The third step, painting, was carried out after the computer lab walls were already


                 clean. This made the paint colour easier to stick to the wall and look more homogenous.




























                                            Computer lab walls are painted with a
                                            harmonious color combination of paint



               Step 4: Designing



                        The last step, designing, was done to further decorate the newly-painted computer

                 lab with customised slogans and infographics.
















                                                             21]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[Computer lab is designed with customised slogans and
                                                         infographics
































                                                  The final look of the repainted wall





                                                             22]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[STAIRS PAINTING



                       Groups 1, 2 and 3 were assigned to paint the stairs. They had to scrape off the stairs with


               the provided scrapers before painting it to allow for the smooth application of the paint, which

               groups 1 and 2 did. All three groups helped in painting the stairs with red, yellow and blue paint

               after the previous paint was finished being scraped off.



                       Group 3 was responsible for painting the letters on the stairs – ‘There Is No Shortcut To


               Success, You Have To Climb The Steps’. They used the Society’s office's computer with the

               permission of the staff to print the words needed to act as an outline before painting it on the stairs,


               each letter cut carefully. The stairs were painted with four layers of paint; it took them half a day

               to finish all the painting on the stairs. At half day, all three groups were in a rush because of their


               need to also help in the PhotoScape class with the children happening at the time.
































                                               Sasikala caught on camera doing her duty







                                                             23]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[Painting the letters for the words


































                                                Painting of the stairs in process






                                                             24]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[ROAD PAINTING



                       For the road painting, groups 6, 7 and 8 were responsible. They first cleared the surface of


               the road, making sure there was no trash on the space that they would be painting on. Then, they

               used a measuring tape to measure the exact length and width of the game – Snakes and Ladders –

               they will paint on it: 25cmx25cm for each of the square on the puzzle. As there were only red,


               yellow and blue paint and they needed green, they mixed blue paint with yellow paint to get green

               paint.



                       They  started drawing snakes and ladders  on the road using crayons  first. Every  group


               member took turn to paint each square. They painted the snakes white with designs on them and

               the ladders with positive words on it such as ‘Kind’ and ‘Honest’.





































                                       Smiling for the camera during the start of their work





                                                             25]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[Dr. Wong helping out the group in painting the road
































                                                        Hard at work















                                                             26]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[COMPUTER LAB SESSION (PHOTOSCAPE CLASS)



                       PhotoScape is a graphic manipulation software, allowing users to easily edit pictures and


               photographs. It promotes a simple user interface to perform common photo enhancements, such as

               colour adjustment, resizing, printing and GIF animation, along with other basic features like photo

               viewer,  photo  editor  and  photo  batch-editor.  PhotoScape  was  chosen  for  this  class  due  to  its


               accessibility and easy-to-use features for all beginners, and it will be a great help to the children in

               Pure Life Society in the future, whether it be in school or their future work place.



                       The  scheduled  basic  PhotoScape  learning  session  was  from  1.30pm  to  3.30pm.


               Introductions by the teaching group were made to the children involved beforehand, while some

               went to the computer lab to install PhotoScape on all the available computers and to make sure


               that all computers had internet connection. As the number of available computers in the lab was

               limited, our class representative, Jia Xian, divided them into pairs for every four children.



                       They started the class by teaching the children about the features of PhotoScape and then

               taught them on how to use the photo editor and GIF animation. They were able to download images


               from the internet and added frames, texts and objects on the images. The children were also showed

               the  mobile  applications  that  the  UM  students  had  created  on  their  own  mobile  phones  to


               demonstrate the use of such software accompanied by an animating software.



















                                                             27]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[Our course representative Jia Xian is patiently guiding a boy


























                                                   Having fun while learning

















                                                             28]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[Our lecturer Dr. Wong is patiently guiding a boy




                       At 3:30pm, the session ended, and the children were dismissed. Overall, the session was


               fun and the children were able to follow the PhotoScape learning session. All the children showed

               great interest toward the graphic manipulation software. At the end of the session, our lecturer Dr.


               Wong said: “To produce a picture of your future using the software is easy, but in real life, you

               have to strive and work hard for it.” We hope we had done a good job in the learning session in


               inspiring the children to learn more in the future.
















                                                             29]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[STEM COMPETITION (DEMONSTRATION OF SCIENCE EXPERIMENTS)





                              VINEGAR, BAKING SODA AND BALLOON EXPERIMENT




















               Materials:


               Empty bottle, balloon, baking soda and table vinegar







               Summary:



                       Pour some vinegar into an empty bottle and put baking soda into a balloon. Carefully

               stretch the neck of the balloon and pull it over the mouth of the bottle without letting any baking


               soda fall into it. Lift up the balloon and let baking soda drop into the bottle and mix with the

               vinegar.



                       Bubbles are released when baking soda is added into vinegar, signaling the appearance of


               gas. The released gas inflates the balloon. Here, the experiment was successful. The balloon was







                                                             30]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[inflated by the released carbon dioxide gas which was produced by the acid-base reaction between

               vinegar (acetic acid) and baking soda (sodium bicarbonate).




                          Chemical Equation: CH3COOH + NaHCO3 → CH3COONa + H2O + CO2







                                       COLOR CHANGING MILK EXPERIMENT
































               Materials:



               Food-coloring, milk and soap







               Summary:



                       The food coloring in milk disperse as soap is added. The fat from the milk and soap work

               hard to join together, which causes the movement.

                                                             31]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[NON-NEWTONIAN FLUID EXPERIMENT























               Materials:



               Water, corn starch and a container







               Summary:



                       Put equal parts of water and corn starch in your chosen container. Rotate the container

               gently and slowly to mix the ingredients together. As long as there is pressure/force on the mixture,


               the mixture will act like a ‘solid’ and when the pressure/force disappears, the mixture will ‘melt’

               like a liquid.



                       Here, the experiment was a success and the final product could be played with and tested.

               The children were fascinated with the solid-fluid consistency and were given free rein to play and


               test the fluid out as they pleased, which interested them greatly.







                                                             32]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[ISSUES/CHALLENGES






               Transportation



                       Unfortunately, we did not have the required time to try and get a bus for an event that

               would come only a few weeks after we were informed of it. Typically, bus services will need a


               month of advance warning before any decision can be made, and even that is not guaranteed,

               especially since UM buses are highly sought after by college projects currently. Fortunately, the


               majority of us managed to agree on an alternative of getting an e-hailing service as our transport

               such as GrabCar and having each group go together to allow for the sharing of the service fee.






               Stairs Painting



                       For the stairs painting, three groups were assigned to this job. However, there was only

               three brushes available to distribute among the three groups. When the paint on the upper stairs

               had dried, the group responsible for the lettering still had to wait for the painting at the lower parts


               to be done by the other groups. This took unnecessary time that made them take a long time to

               complete the whole painting of the stairs and they were then late for the evening session on the


               PhotoScape class. There should have been at least two brushes for each group so that between

               them, they could have taken turns while also allowing for the other brush to be used to settle the


               letterings on the part of the stairs that have dried.









                                                             33]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[NEWSPAPER TEMPLATE



                                  UCE GKR1016 CLASS WITH PURE LIFE SOCIETY





































               KUALA LUMPUR, 18 NOV – On Sunday 18 November 2018, students of Basic Graphics Using


               Computer class from University of Malaya visited Pure Life Society at Jalan Puchong, Kuala

               Lumpur, as part of their co-curriculum course fulfilment. A total of 41 students were included in

               the trip, along with their supervising lecturer Dr. Wong Seng Yue. The main objective of the visit


               was to contribute to the society’s betterment by empowering the underprivileged children with

               knowledge. The visit was scheduled to be from 7.30 a.m. until 5.30 p.m.



                       Various activities were carried out by the group of students, some activities benefiting the

               orphanage and care home’s facilities and environment, while others were to the benefit of the


               children there. During the morning, stairs were repainted by the visiting students, a mural was

               drawn  on  one  of  the  walls,  and  a  board  game  was  painted  onto  the  road  for  the  children’s



                                                             34]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[amusement.  Later in the evening, a PhotoScape class was held by the students for the children, in

               which the children were taught the basics of photo manipulation using the software PhotoScape



                       There was also a STEM competition held after the class was finished, whereby the UM

               students  demonstrated  several  STEM  experiments  to  the  children.  STEM  is  an  acronym  for


               Science,  Technology,  Engineering,  and  Math,  and  the  theme  for  the  course  this  year.  The

               experiments showcased were mainly of the science branch, under physics, chemistry and biology.


               The science experiments were a huge attraction for the children with their ever-inquisitive minds.


                       The visit ended near 6 p.m., a bit over the supposed ending time, with a closing ceremony


               and a group photo.


















































                                                             35]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[CLOSURE



                       The event was a huge success. Although the funds received were not aplenty, the memories


               we got in return were enough to gloss over the little bit of hardship we had during the planning

               stage. The spirit of sharing and cooperation between all the students in regard to the money needed

               to organise the visit were heart-warming and bore the much-needed reminder that in times of


               hardship, there is always kindness from others that would lessen the heaviness of any burden.

               Seeing the smiles on the children’s face was as rewarding as if we had won the lottery for a RM1


               million cheque.


                       ‘There Is No Shortcut To Success, You Have To Climb The Steps’ – these are the words


               we painted upon one of the stairs in Pure Life Society. Hopefully, the children, as they climb the

               stairs,  will  always  remember  the  visiting  University  of  Malaya  students  that  came  to  impart


               knowledge to them and will by themselves continue to pursue further knowledge in hopes of

               bettering themselves and to become the next educators to a different group of children.





























                                                             36]]></page></pages></Search>