<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="33"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[[Document title]




                                                   [Document subtitle]


































































                                                   AMMAR ZUHAIR BIN ISMAIL
                                                   [COMPANY NAME]]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[TABLE OF CONTENTS


         NO       DESCRIPTIONS                                             PAGE


         A        About the Course                                         2


         B        About UCE                                                2


         C        Lecturer’s Note                                          2


         D        Our Responsibility                                       3



         1        Name of Programme/Department/Faculty                     7


         2        Name of Project                                          7


         3        Name of Lecturer/ Team Leaders                           7


         4        Date of Project                                          7


         5.a)     Background                                               8



         5.b)     Objective                                                10


         5.c)     Stakeholders                                             10


         5.d)     Question                                                 10


         5.e)     Name of Participants (Pure Life Society)                 10


         5.f)     Number of Volunteers (UM)                                10


         5.g)     Duration of Execution                                    10


         5.h)     Execution                                                11



         5.i)     Issues/ Challenges                                       30


         6        Newspaper Template                                       31


         7        Closure                                                  32


                  Appendices


                                                            1]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[A) About The Course


        GNEK1026 - BASICS OF COMPUTER GRAPHICS
               This course exposes students to the basic techniques in the art of graphics using computer such as

        operating, determining the size, choosing appropriate colours and themes. Students will also learn the

        various techniques and tools to produce graphics in the computer. Through this course, students’ interest
        will be nurtured in graphics using computer via teamwork activities. Teaching and learning will be

        conducted through experiential learning and collective problem solving with the community.
        At the end of this course, students are able to understand and practise the basic techniques in the art of

        graphics using computer and capable of becoming a citizen with an inquisitive mind based on interest.




            B) About UCE
               University Community Engagement known as UCE among University of Malaya is a program

        initiated by Center for Initiation of Talent and Industrial Training-CITRA University of Malaya to inculcate
        human values among undergraduates. It is important for the future graduates to build a holistic character

        which includes their love for the community. CITRA is on the right track as they value this so much by

        implementing UCE. UCE is conducted by each co-curriculum course students as a requirement to pass the
        subject. Students usually plan and execute the whole volunteering program on their own. This enhances the

        organisational skills among the undergraduates.

























                                                            2]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Group 1 – Logistic and Resource Bureau





















                                     Toh Kek Yoong                       EEE140124

                                     Ma Song Jun                         REA140016

                                     Lee Chong Leong                     EEE140048
                                     Lai Chia Yee                        EEE140046




        Our Jobscopes :

              To prepare all the resources that needed during the UCE visit to Pure Life Society.
              To arrange transport for UCE visit to Pure Life Society.

              To contact with Pure Life Society People In Charge for UCE.

              To provide Photoscape Designing Tutorial Classes for the Pupils of Pure Life Society.
              To provide Powerpoint Tutorial Classes for the Pupils of Pure Life Society.

              To join the mural painting during the UCE.














                                                            3]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Group 2 – Photography and Videography Bureau





















                                 Gurpal Kaur A/P Jugjit Singh               AEP140017

                                 Yap Onn Sang                               AEL140027

                                 Jurairat Minsa-Ait                          IET140702
                                 Miss Husana Baite                           IET140703

                                 Chong Hor Men                              KES140005
                                 Nur Sahira Azra Binti Roslan               SEP140040




        Our Jobscopes :

              To arrange a photoshoot session of the whole GNEK1026 team with the pupils and administrators of
               Pure Life Society.

              To document each team activities by taking pictures and videos.

              To edit photos and video took in the UCE.
              To provide Photoscape Designing Tutorial Classes for the Pupils of Pure Life Society.

              To provide Powerpoint Tutorial Classes for the Pupils of Pure Life Society.

              To join the mural painting during the UCE.









                                                            4]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Group 3 – Programme Planning and Gift Bureau





















                                 Mohd Hanapi Bin Yakap                      SER130015

                                 Loo Yong Xin                               SEH140005

                                 Phua Chai Hao                              LEB140096
                                 Mahan Dastgiri                             SEU130702

                                 Lydia Li Man Yan                           KES140010



        Our Jobscopes :



              To plan and ensure programme flow is carry out smoothly.
              To conduct and in charge of the program during UCE.

              To provide Photoscape Designing Tutorial Classes for the Pupils of Pure Life Society.

              To provide Powerpoint Tutorial Classes for the Pupils of Pure Life Society.

              To join the mural painting during the UCE.












                                                            5]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Group 4 – Finance and Secretarial Bureau





















                                 Ammar Zuhair Bin Ismail                    KEA120007

                                 Obaidallah Ibrahim Mohamed Elshafiey       SEH140005

                                 Muhammad Khairul Nizam Bin Md Yusof  KEA110028
                                 Syed Muzammil Iqbal                        KEK130703

                                 Brandon Mark Nyaru                         KEM120009



        Our Jobscopes :



              To manage and control the UCE budget.
              To collect fundings and document the receipts systematically.

              To prepare meeting minutes and paper works.

              To provide Photoscape Designing Tutorial Classes for the Pupils of Pure Life Society.

              To provide Powerpoint Tutorial Classes for the Pupils of Pure Life Society.
              To join the mural painting during the UCE.











                                                            6]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[Name of Programme/ Department/ Faculty

        GNEK 1026  Basics of Computer Graphics
        Co-Curriculum Course

        Center for Initiation of Talent and Industrial Training – CITRA




        Name of Project
        University Engagement Programme (UCE) at Pure Life Society




        Name of Course Coordinator/ Lecturer

        Dr. Wong Seng Yue



        Name of Bureau Leader

        Toh Kek Yoong                       Logistic and Resource Bureau

        Gurpal Kaur A/P Jugjit Singh        Photograhy and Videography Bureau
        Mohd Hanapi Bin Yakap               Programme Planning and Gift Bureau

        Ammar Zuhair Bin Ismail             Finance and Secretarial Bureau



        Date of Project

           th
        22  April 2018



















                                                            7]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Organizational Background


        Generally, Pure Life Society is a non-profit organization (NGO)
        actively serving the orphans and underprivileged children aged 7

        to 17 years old. This center was established 67 years ago and still

        standing strong at Batu 6, Jalan Puchong, Wilayah Persekutuan
        Kuala Lumpur, 58200, Kuala Lumpur.


             From the very beginning, Pure Life Society upholds a genuine
        mission  to  promote  the  spirit  of  unity  in  the  face  of  diversity

        through service to the community irrespective of race or, religion. For the realization of the mission, Pure Life

        Society’s committee members have instilled strong belief among all in which recognizes all things as one.
        They believe in One God, One World and One Race. This message directly interprets that well-being is for

        all human being without any biases or discrimination towards the children. These children deserve to live a
        good and peaceful life like anybody else; it is their human rights. Decent live here refers to availability of

        good opportunity of education which then leads to career success.

             Basically, Pure Life Society is engaged with four main activities for the kids. Below are those activities:-


            1.  Spiritual Activities

                     To promote respect and appreciation of all religious schools of thought
                     Example: Reciting prayers before meal

            2.  Sports Activities

                     To ensure children are actively and physically fit.
                     Successfully built badminton courts and futsal ground for the kids to play

            3.  Vocational Education Activities

                     Importance given to skills
                     Few  children  have  sent  off  to  vocational  colleges  (e.g.  TEKAT  college  in  Kajang  for

                       automobile technology training)

                     Other skills activities include Yoga and Indian classical dance
            4.  Facilities

                     Some  great  facilities  have  been  organized  in  the  center  including  free  medical  check-up,

                       laundry sewing and handicraft, library, computer labs and bread-making services.








                                                            8]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[Historical Background


               H.H. Swami Satyananda (picture on left), born in 1906, was the Founder-President of the Pure Life
        Society, who, during the years 1945 to 1951, was involved in relief work among the poor, the orphans, and

        the displaced children both in Malaya and Singapore. At that time, Mother (then Sister) Mangalam, the present

        President now, was already working closely with him. In the year 1949, he started off the Pure Life Society
        as a paper organization, aiming to promote multi-racial and multi religious understanding through lectures,

                                          forums  and  programs  that  promote  interaction  through  inter-faith
                                          conventions and services somewhere at the Leper settlement, old folks’

                                          homes, Serendah Boys’ Home and the like.


                                            After that, the Society was registered in 1950, July 15 and found the
                                          need to establish a home for orphans and underprivileged children left and

                                          resulted from World War II. Eventually, in 1952, the first few barrack-like
                                          buildings were put up by the Pure Life Society.


                                            In 1961, following Swami Satyananda’s demise, Mother (then Sister)
                                          Mangalam  was  appointed  as  President  by  the  virtue  of  the  Society’s

                                          Ordinance.


































                                                            9]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[OBJECTIVE


        1. To build up a caring community

        2. To give back to the society


        3. To promote the positive values of self-fulfillment

        4. To empower under privileged children


        5. To utilize community resources


        6. To enhance the sense of social belongings




            STAKEHOLDERS

        Children of Pure Life Society





        IS IT THE FIRST TIME YOU JOINED THIS PROGRAMME WITH THIS

        COMMUNITY? PLEASE STATE (1st time, 2nd time, etc.)


        Yes, it is our first time to join this UCE programme with the community and contribute

        something to them





            NUMBER OF PARTICIPANT FROM THIS COMMUNITY THAT INVOLVED

        52 students




            NUMBER OF PARTICIPANT FROM UM THAT IS INVOLVED


        20 students




            PROJECT PROGRESSION PERIOD


        9 hours and 30 minutes





                                                           10]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[Tentative UCE


                    nd
        Date      : 22  April 2018
        Venue   : The Pure Life Society, Jalan Puchong


              Time                                                                      Activities

         0815 – 0830                  Participants will gather at DTC plains before departure


         0830 – 0900                  Depart to The Pure Life Society

         0900 – 1000                  Breakfast / Ice Breaking

         1000 – 1200                  Team A – Computer Lessons Session


                                      •      Power Point Presentation

                                      •      PhotoScape

                                      Team B – Staircase Painting


         1200 – 1300                  Lunch / Prayer Zohor

         1300 – 1500                  Team A - Computer Lessons Session

                                      •      Power Point Presentation

                                      •      PhotoScape


                                      Team B - Staircase Painting

         1500 – 1600                  Tea Time Rest

         1600 – 1700                  Buffering (Solve all activities)

         1700 – 1730                  Interaction Session (Program Bureau)


         1730 – 1745                  Move home





















                                                           11]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[Main Activities


        Basically, we have two main activities that were successfully conducted in the orphanage centre. These
        activities include teaching children the basis of computer skills and painting the staircases. Our teams have

        divided into two division whereby each was in-charge of those planned activities and took turn afterwards

        for the next session. Therefore, all of us had the opportunity to conduct two separate tasks.

        Basis of computer skills


        Here, we have assisted the children to explore Microsoft Power Point and PhotoScape computer
        applications. For the presentation. We have earlier decided to have five main matters in which the children

        were asked to write down key points. Each presentation was subjected to 6 to 7 number of slides. The
        matters include:-


        1) About Myself


        2) Living Habits/ Hobby in Pure Life

        3) My Favourite Sports/ TV shows


        4) My Ambition

        5) How to Achieve Goal


        Besides, we have also educated the children in using PhotoScape effectively. Children were taught to have

        some fun with photo editing that enables them to fix and enhance photos. Many of them have added frames,
        texts and drawing some shapes. Since they were beginner, we tried our best to focus only simple yet useful

        matters on PhotoScape.

        Staircase painting


        This task requires us to paint up staircases with vibrant colours together with writing up some motivational

        quote. Red, blue and yellow were the colours chosen to paint up and on the bottom of the staircase, quote
        was written with black colour wordings.

















                                                           12]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[Staircases painted with attractive colours

































         A quote dedicated for the children at Pure Life Society


















                                                           13]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[Group Photo Taking and Interview Session


               After having our lunch at the dining hall, we had our first group photo session around 2 p.m. at the
        multipurpose hall as the hall is big enough to fit all our classmates and children. After that, we continued with

        the PhotoScape learning session with the children.

               Then, we had an interview session for all the classmates and our lecturer, Dr. Wong. In this session,

        we shared our opinions and experiences that we have gained from the activities. Everyone took turn to ask

        questions randomly and recorded the responses from the classmates. The interview questions are as follows:

            i.     How was your volunteering service programme here?

            ii.    Can you describe your experience in Pure Life Society in one sentence?
            iii.   Do you think more young people should come and participate in such volunteer programme?

            iv.    What are the benefits of joining this sort of volunteer programme?

            v.     How was the service given in Pure Life Society?
            vi.    How can we attract more young people to participate in social work or volunteer service willingly?

            vii.   How can the younger people be brought into service in homes like the Pure Life Society?

               After the interview session, the videos recorded were compiled before passing to the person in charge

        of Pure Life Society. The main purpose of the interview session is to attract more people to participate in

        volunteer activities in the future.

               Before  we  went  back  to  University  of  Malaya,  we  had  another  group  photo  session  with  all  the

        classmates and children there, this time with the principal included.

































                                                 The First Group Photo

                                                           14]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[The Second Group Photo


































                                                           15]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[Basic PhotoScape and PowerPoint Learning


               PhotoScape is a graphics editing program, allowing users to easily edit photographs. It provides a
        simple user interface to perform common photo enhancements including colour adjustment, resizing, printing

        and GIF animation. PhotoScape has features such as photo viewer, photo editor, photo batch-editor, page
        creator,  GIF  animation,  featured  printer,  screen  capture,  colour  picker,  RAW  converter  and  face  finder.

        PhotoScape is chosen for its accessibility and easy-to-use feature for beginners. Microsoft PowerPoint is a
        tool to create presentation slides. Every student needs to master the skill of using PowerPoint to do slides for

        academic presentations and event presentations. These two tools are chosen for the learning session to prepare

        the kids in Pure Life Society in the future. They will need these skills whether in school or work place.

               The  scheduled  Basic  PhotoScape  and  Microsoft  PowerPoint  learning  session  was  from  9:30  am.

        Before the session started, we introduced ourselves to the kids in Pure Life Society. Some of us went to the
        computer lab to install PhotoScape on all the available computers, and to make sure that all computers had

        internet connection. As the number of available computers in the lab was limited, we had to divide into groups
        for the learning session. Our class representative, Ma Song Jun divided us into pairs, that each pair had to

        teach four kids. We had a total of four sessions; two sessions with senior boys and junior boys in the morning,
        two sessions with senior girls in the afternoon. Each session took around one hour and fifteen minutes. For

        the first session, only three groups went to the computer lab due to limited number of computers. We then had

        interactions with other two groups of kids and taught them to use photo-editing application that are available
        in our phones.


               We started off the learning session by teaching the kids about the features of PhotoScape. The kids
        were taught on how to use photo editor and GIF animation. They were able to download images from the

        internet, and add frames, texts and objects on the images. Then, they were taught on preparing presentation
        slides by using PowerPoint. The theme of the session was about themselves as required by the Principal of

        Pure Life Society. They were required to do slides about their biodata, life in Pure Life Society, family, school,
        ambition, best friends, and skills. They were able to write points for each slide, and to decorate the slides with

        their creativity. Throughout the session, the guys were excited, whereas the girls are quieter when they were

        doing their slides. The kids were guided and interaction was observed between kids and facilitators.



















                                                           16]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[Loo Yong Xin was guiding a junior boy in PhotoScape.





































                                Mahan is guiding a senior boy in doing presentation slides.












                                                           17]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[The junior boys are having fun while learning.







































                       The pupils were taught on preparing presentation slides by using PowerPoint.








                                                           18]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[Our lecturer Dr. Wong was patiently guiding a junior boy.



               At 4:30pm, the session ended and the pupils were dismissed. Overall, the session was fun and the

        pupils were able to follow this PhotoScape Learning session. All pupils showed great interest towards the
        graphical processing software. At the end of the session, our lecturer Dr. Wong said: ‘To produce a picture of

        your future using the software is easy, but in real life, you have to strive and work hard for it.’ We hope we

        had done a good job in the learning session as well as inspiring the pupils towards a better future.

























                                                           19]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[Staircase Painting Activity


               The “Staircase Painting” activity was delegated to 5 students, namely Ammar, Khairul, Lydia, Chia
        Yee and Muzammil who came from 4 different groups. The activity involved 4 processes, beginning with

        cleaning and continued by layering with white paint, and the finishing touch which is designing.

























             (From left to right)Khairul, Ammar and Muzammil were setting up before beginning the “Staircase
                                                    Painting” activity


        Step 1: Cleaning


               The first step, cleaning is to ensure that dust and dirt were removed in order to allow the smooth
        layering of white paint on the surface of the staircase.























                                Chia Yee and Lydia were cleaning the staircase with broom
                                                           20]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[Step 2: Layering


               This process involved the coating of the staircase’s surface with white paint so that the designing
        step can be conducted. This is because white paint allows the coloured paint to intact smoothly on the

        surface.



























                                The students were “layering” the staircase with white paint


        Step 3: Designing


               Designing process involved painting the staircase with red, blue and yellow colour and inserting the
        quote “There is no shortcut to success, you have to climb the steps” with black colour paint.




                                                                                      The students were painting

                                                                                      the staircase with red, blue
                                                                                        and yellow colour paint



















                                                           21]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[The result of

                                                                                           completed ‘Staircase

                                                                                           Painting’ activity
















































                                                           22]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[STAIRCASE

                                                                   PAINTING

                Upon reaching the Pure Life

                Society at about 9.00am, we       1.                                                         2.

                were    gathered    in   the
                multipurpose. Basic briefing

                were  given  by  Our  Team
                Leader     regarding     the
                planning  that  needed  to  be

                completed by the end of the
                day.  Then,  the  designated

                groups  that  responsible  for
                staircase   painting    were
                gathered outside of the hall


                waiting    for   the    next

                command  by  the  Team           3.                                                          4.
                Leader.  After  receiving  the
                                                 Pic. 1-3: Our Team Leader explaining on what to do on that day
                order,  the  first  thing  we
                execute  was  cleaning  the      Pic. 4: Our lecturer, Dr. Wong reminded us to take photos as many as
                                                 we can during the UCE.
                staircase.

                                                                                                           st
                During the painting process occurred, the staircase which connected the ground floor to 1
                floor had to be closed momentarily for allowing the volunteers to do their job without any

                distraction. So,  this  ramp  that  is  located  in  front  of  the  multipurpose  hall  served  as  their

                                                                                  st
                alternative route from the hall to the library that is located on the 1  floor.

























                                                           23]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[Before we started the painting process, we must

                                                        make  sure  the  surface  of  the  staircase  is  clean
                                                        from dust and any contaminants. Right away, the

                                                        girls grabbed the brooms and start to sweep the
                                                        stairways. We were noticed that the first top five

                                                        of the staircase were wet and some contain some

                                                        amount of water. So, without wasting any time the

                                                        boys grabbed some old newspaper and started to

                                                        dry  the  surface.  Because  of  the  some  of  the
                                                        staircase were so wet the newspaper trick doesn’t

                                                        do  that  well.  So  we  needed  something  that  can

                                                        hold the water. The best option is a rag, but we
                                                        doesn’t have that luxury. We need to think fast as

                                                        the water won’t evaporate itself and we need to

                                                        start  painting  as  soon  as  possible.  So  we  tried

                                                        using a paintbrush to push the water out of the
                                                        way. Hey, this method work although it’s a little

                                                        bit slow. After majority of the water were gone, we

                                                        dried the surface with some newspaper.








































                                                           24]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[After drafting, we start

                                                                                    to  paint  the  stair  with
                                                                                    the white color paint to

                                                                                    eliminate the defect on

                                                                                    the  stair.  Some  of  us
                                                                                    paint at the top of the

                                                                                    stair,  some  of  us  also

                                                                                    paint  in  the  middle  of

                                                                                    stair  and  some  of  us
                                                                                    paint  at  bottom  of  the

                                                                                    stair. As we could see,

                                                                                    the  cooperation  and
                                                                                    coordination  between

                                                                                    members      are   very
                                                                                    important  in  mural

                                                                                    painting     is    very

                                                                                    important  in  mural

                                                                                    painting to shorten up
                                                                                    the time used.





                 As you can see, painting staircase is much more difficult and much more tiring as we need

                 to squat a lot as the surface needed to paint is much lower compared to a normal wall. The
                 total time we needed to complete the whole surface of the staircase with undercoat colour is

                 about an hour. After that, we needed to let the undercoat colour to fully dry before we can

                 start to paint with the designated colour.







                                                           25]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[Different issues were monitored while discussion including cleaning of the site and staircase

                 and thinking of using attractive combination of colours for painting. The plan was to use a
                 combination  of  red,  yellow  and  blue  colours  to  paint  the  staircase  and  the  work  was


                 distributed among the group members.





















                After the lunch break, we come back to continue ours work and we start our painting with

                quotes on the stair. Firstly, we counted the staircase step numbers in order to distribute the
                quotes evenly. So, we decided to place the quotes every two steps. One of our member trace

               the quotes with pencil first, to avoid spelling mistake. We colour the quotes with black paint.





















              Each student got the opportunity to show their painting skills and the team work was worth

              appreciating. After the painting was done, a beautiful quote was written on the stairs reminding
              that hard work should be done to achieve success in life.



                                                           26]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[Students discussing about the plan of

                                                                  painting the staircase

















                                                                  Students preparing the paint before the
                                                                  painting process















                                                                    What a team work!!!!









                                                           27]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[‘THERE IS NO SHORTCUT TO SUCCESS,


                           YOU HAVE TO CLIMB THE STEPS’






















































                                                           28]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[HOUSTON, WE HAVE A

          PROBLEM. WE NEED

          MORE PEOPLE. IT’S
          ALMOST 5PM!

















                                                                       After eight hours of working, we finally
                                                                       finished  the  stairs.  At  first,  we  start  to

                                                                       worry the painting is not quite beautiful

                                                                       and interesting. However, the painting is
                                                                       quite nice and satisfied to watch it.
















               Last touch before we finished the day…
















                                                           29]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[ISSUE FACED AND ACTION TAKEN TO OVERCOME THEM

            1.  PAINTING AND BRUSH EQUIPMENT

                   a.  Before we start our mural painting, there are a few things we need to consider. One thing would
                       be  the  cost  of  our  painting  equipment.  As  there  is  no  equipment  provided  by  the  PLS,

                       everything was on our own. Few weeks before the event, we decided our theme and started to

                       buy the paint including the equipment. Painting the staircase would require 1 litre of white
                       paint, and also 0.5 litre of red, blue and white paint. To make everything easier, we decided to

                       share among our group and was half funded by Dr Wong. The decision to share was one of the
                       best decision since it put less burden on us student incorporate with our community engagement

                       program.

            2.  TRANSPORTATION
                   a.  As  a  student,  most  of  us  does  not  have  any  transportation  for  the  community  program.

                       Fortunately, some of us does own a car so we decided to carpooling since we our computer
                       graphic course only consist of 21 people. We shared among us for the fuel and toll required for

                       the journey. One of our group leader brought a truck to the party and we load up all our painting
                       equipment to the truck for the mural painting event.

            3.  MURAL PAINTING

                   a.  During the mural painting event, 5 people were allocated for the event since most of us were
                       in another program of transferring knowledge to the PLS children. The 5 people involve in the

                       group were good friends and they cooperation and coordination speeds up the painting event
                       and they were able to finish in time for the painting. They work hand in hand as thus make the

                       event easier to handle while making friends with each other.
            4.  RESTRICTION AREA

                   a.  During  our  UCE  event,  most  of  the  PLS  children  were  on  the  building  for  their  classes.

                       Unfortunately, the staircase we were painting on were their main way to their class. In order
                       for them to not step on the painting while it is still wet and make a mess of their building, we

                       decided to restrict the area of the staircase in order for us to do our mural painting easily and

                       make our comrades jobs easier.












                                                           30]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[Newspaper Template

        UNIVERSITY COMMUNITY ENGANGEMENT (UCE) OF BASICS OF COMPUTER
        GRAPHICS STUDENT

























              nd
        On 22  APRIL 2018, a group of undergraduates from University of Malaya organized a visit to Pure Life
        Society, Jalan Puchong, Kuala Lumpur. This visit was a part of the fulfilment for the co-curriculum course,
        Basics of Computer Graphics.


               20 students under the supervision and guidance of lecturer Dr. Wong Seng Yue carried out the 8 hours

        visit to the orphanage and care home with the main objective of contributing to the society’s betterment and
        empowering underprivileged children who were housed in Pure Life Society.


               As finalized during planning stages, the students from University of Malaya managed to successfully
        carry out and conduct various activities such as interaction session, staircase painting, PowerPoint class and

        PhotoScape class.


               After the briefing  session, they  broke up  into 2 groups where the  students began the transferring
        knowledge session and also with the mural painting session. After lunch and afternoon prayers, the students

        proceeded to guide the children of Pure Life Society to utilize the PhotoScape application, which can be used
        to edit pictures and graphic materials. After that session ended the students conducted a career aptitude survey

        where the children were evaluated of their career choices and areas of interest which they could pursue as
        careers. Finally, the students also conducted mini games with the children of Pure Life Society. The mural

        painting session was finish at 4.30pm.


               The visit ended at 5pm after a special briefing by PLS chief administrator, Mr Pratap who commended
        the students’ efforts and commitment towards the society. He also urged students to be involved on a regular

        basis to help underprivileged children.




                                                           31]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[CLOSURE


               After the event, we as a group achieved a few things together. Despite less allocated fund was given,

        our sincerity to motivate the children through mural painting overtook the feelings of tired and laziness. Even
        we spend less for the children but we achieved more than what we look for. Our decision to share expenses

        make it less burden for us and working together in order to make the program a success. Beautiful mural

        painting can be achieved with the help from each other.

               In accordance with our theme for the stairs which is; THERE IS NO SHORTCUT TO SUCCESS YOU

        NEED TO CLIMB THE STEPS. The theme was in line with the stairs where the children of PLS would be
        motivated by the words every time they climb the stairs on their way to class. If the mural painting could spark

        the children motivation whenever they are down in life we have achieved our mission for the UCE program.


               Last, the staff of PLS were quite happy with the end results and no better reward could match their
        smile and compliment we get at the end of the day.

















































                                                           32]]></page></pages></Search>